Guide to the Boswell Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alexander Boswell (1707-1782), 1548-1781; Series XVI; 16.25; (37 boxes)
  - LAND PURCHASES
    - Carbello
      - Inventories of the writs, 1666-1762 (Box 139, Folder 2537-40)
      - Progresses of the writs
        Darfad
        - Life-rent to George Vallance, 1635 (Box 139, Folder 2541)
        - Gass and Welltrees
          - Special retour for James Cunningham, 1588 (Box 139, Folder 2542)
          - Charter of Gass by Whitfoord to Campbell
          - Sasine of Welltrees for John Beg, 1700 (Box 139, Folder 2543)
          - Sasine and decreet for John Beg, 1765 (Box 139, Folder 2544-45)
          - Dispositions for Alexander Mitchell of Halglenmuir, 1765-67 (Box 139, Folder 2546)
          - Disposition by Mitchell to Boswell, 1767 (Box 139, Folder 2547)
        - McClellanstown
          - Charters and confirmations for John Wallace of Dundonald, 1552-53 (Box 139, Folder 2548-49)
          - Charter for Edward Wallace, 1571 (Box 139, Folder 2550)
          - Charter and sasine for Quintagern Boswell and Margaret Wyllie, 1640 (Box 139, Folder 2551)
          - Charter, 1651 (Box 139, Folder 2552)
          - Charters for Andro Brown, 1655 (Box 139, Folder 2553)
          - Sasine for John and James Wallace, 1743 (Box 139, Folder 2554)
          - Charter of resignation, 1743 (Box 139, Folder 2555)
        - Stainbriggs
          Charter by Ffailford
          Charter by the Wallaces
          - Charters and sasines for George Reid, 1604-07 (Box 140, Folder 2556-57)
          - See also: Box 162, folders 2892-93 (Box 140, Folder 2556-57)
          - Wadset discharge, 1607 (Box 140, Folder 2558)
          - Sasine for Boswell, 1609 (Box 140, Folder 2559)
          - Charter of confirmation on a suit of novel darein, 1630 (Box 140, Folder 2560)
          - Charter from Whitfoord to Wallace, 1632 (Box 140, Folder 2561)
          - Sasines for Campbell, 1644 (Box 140, Folder 2562)
          - Charter for Andro Browne, 1648 (Box 140, Folder 2563)
          - Ratification and sasines by David Boswell for Andro Browne, 1668 (Box 140, Folder 2564-65)
          - Suits against Browne by Wyllie and Reid, 1677 (Box 140, Folder 2566-67)
          - Disposition by Reid to Wallace, 1678 (Box 140, Folder 2568)
          - Charter by Wallace for John Beg, 1687 (Box 140, Folder 2569)
          - Dispositions by Beg to Wallace, 1695, 1699 (Box 140, Folder 2570-71)
          - Sasine for John Beg, 1700 (Box 140, Folder 2572)
        - Wallacetown and general
          - Sasine for James Wallace, 1627 (Box 141, Folder 2573)
          - Sasine for Wallacetown from Mungo Boswell of Duncanziemore, 1631 (Box 141, Folder 2574)
          - Charter by R. Wallace to Thomas Browne, 1647 (Box 141, Folder 2575)
          - Disposition by Lord Cochrane to William Cochrane, [1666?] (Box 141, Folder 2576)
          - Sasine and charter for Andro Brown, 1668 (Box 141, Folder 2577-78)
          - Disposition and charter for James Wallace, 1673 (Box 141, Folder 2579-80)
          - Sasine for Jean Campbell, 1674 (Box 141, Folder 2581)
          - Disposition and sasine by Wyllie to John Beg, 1681, 1687 (Box 141, Folder 2582-83)
          - Disposition by Brown to James Wallace, 1699 (Box 141, Folder 2584)
          - Sasine of an annual rent for William Ferguson, 1700 (Box 141, Folder 2585)
          - Decreet for John Wallace against Brown, 1708 (Box 141, Folder 2586)
          - Disposition to Wallace, 1710 (Box 141, Folder 2587)
          - Sasine for John Beg, 1713 (Box 141, Folder 2588)
          - Disposition and sasine for John and James Wallace, 1743 (Box 141, Folder 2589-90)
          - Annual rent for Joseph Allan, 1755, 1758 (Box 142, Folder 2591-92)
          - Adjudication for Allan against Wallace, 1759 (Box 142, Folder 2593)
          - Charter and sasine for Joseph Allan, 1760 (Box 142, Folder 2594-95)
          - Bond by Wallace for Allan, 1761 (Box 142, Folder 2596)
          - Sasine for Joseph Allan, 1761 (Box 142, Folder 2597)
          - Sasines by Wallace for Alexander Boswell, 1761-62 (Box 142, Folder 2598-2600)
          - "Note concerning Wallacetown's lands", 1762 (Box 142, Folder 2601)
          - "Wallacetown's debt to Allan", 1762 (Box 142, Folder 2602)
          - Disposition by Allan to James McAdam, 1763 (Box 142, Folder 2603)
          - Disposition by Wallace and Allan to Boswell, 1763 (Box 142, Folder 2604)
          - Clare constat by Boswell of Waltree for Beg, 1764 (Box 142, Folder 2605)
          - "Wallace's debt", 1765-73 (Box 142, Folder 2606-07)
          - Sasine of an annual rent for John Loudoun McAdam, 1773 (Box 142, Folder 2608)
          - Annual rent for Joseph Allan, 1754-55 (Box 143, Folder 2609-10)
          - Disposition by John Loudoun McAdam to Hugh Logan, 1774 (Box 143, Folder 2611)
          - Encumbrances on the estate, 1775-78 (Box 143, Folder 2612)
          - Disposition by Hugh Logan to Alexander Boswell, 1779 (Box 143, Folder 2613-14)
          - Assignation by William Wallace to Alexander Boswell, 1779 (Box 143, Folder 2615)
          - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 143, Folder 2616)
          - Wrapper, n.d. (Box 143, Folder 2617)
    - Clews purchase
      - Inventories of the writs, 1705, 1753, n.d. (Box 143, Folder 2618-19)
      - Progresses of the writs
        Clews 22 shilling land ("Overclewshouse")
        Charter and confirmation to John Campbell
        Charter by King James to David Campbell
        Clews 22 shilling land: Campbell
        - Charter by John Campbell to David Campbell, 1590 (Box 143, Folder 2620)
        - Clare constat and sasine by the Earl of Loudoun to John Campbell, 1621 (Box 143, Folder 2621)
        - Discharge of wadset by David Boswell to Campbell, 1626 (Box 143, Folder 2622)
        - Retour and sasines for John Campbell, 1644 (Box 143, Folder 2623-24)
        - Retour and sasine for John Campbell, 1681 (Box 143, Folder 2625)
        - Sasine of an annual rent by John Campbell for William and Alexander Campbell, 1681 (Box 143, Folder 2625)
        - Disposition of an annual rent by John Campbell to James Begg, 1684 (Box 143, Folder 2626)
        - Disposition and sasine by John Campbell for William Campbell, 1688 (Box 143, Folder 2627)
        - Disposition and sasine by William Campbell to James Begg, 1689 (Box 144, Folder 2628)
        - Confirmations by Campbell, 1689-96 (Box 144, Folder 2629-30)
        - Dispositions and sasines by John Begg to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1706 (Box 144, Folder 2631-32)
        - Suits for debt, 1706-07 (Box 144, Folder 2633-35)
        - Clews 22 shilling land: Mitchell
          - Charter and sasine for John Mitchell, 1643 (Box 144, Folder 2636)
          - Sasine and discharge for Mitchell, 1672, 1674 (Box 144, Folder 2637)
          - Marriage provisions of John Mitchell and Christian Kay, 1675 (Box 144, Folder 2638)
          - Suit against John and William Mitchell, 1677 (Box 144, Folder 2639)
          - Inhibition of John Kay against Mitchell, 1679 (Box 144, Folder 2639)
          - Dispositions to John Mitchell, 1680-81 (Box 144, Folder 2640)
          - Sasine and life-rent provisions for William Mitchell, 1682-83 (Box 144, Folder 2641-42)
          - Assignation by John Kay to James Begg, 1689 (Box 144, Folder 2643)
          - Disposition and sasine to John Mitchell, 1689 (Box 144, Folder 2644-45)
          - Disposition and sasine by John Mitchell to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1705 (Box 144, Folder 2646)
      - Mossyde (Meiklewood)
        Charter and confirmation for Andrew Fisher
        Clare constat for Robert Fisher
        - Disposition and sasine by John Campbell to James Law, 1694 (Box 145, Folder 2647-48)
        - Obligation by Law to James Begg, 1702 (Box 145, Folder 2649)
        - Disposition and sasine by James Law to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1705 (Box 145, Folder 2650)
      - Mossroom in Clewsyde
        - Charter and sasine for Thomas Mitchell, 1566, 1577 (Box 145, Folder 2651)
        - Charter and sasine to Janet and John Mitchell, 1591 (Box 145, Folder 2652)
      - Netherclews
        - Charter and sasine for James McLanochan, 1579 (Box 145, Folder 2653)
        - Royal charter and sasines for James McLanochan (Box 145, Folder 2654-55)
        - Charters and sasines by McLanochan for George Campbell, 1600 (Box 145, Folder 2656)
        - Sasine by George Campbell to Margaret Campbell, 1600 (Box 145, Folder 2657)
        - Charter by Lord Loudoun confirming the charter to George Campbell
        - Sasine for George Campbell, 1605, 1644 (Box 145, Folder 2658)
        - Charter and sasine by George Campbell to Hugh and Matthew Campbell, 1641 (Box 145, Folder 2659)
        - Bonds by John Campbell to Isobell Reid, 1663, 1667 (Box 145, Folder 2660)
        - Disposition by George Campbell to Mungo Campbell of Netherplace, 1681 (Box 145, Folder 2661)
        - Backbond by George Campbell to Mungo Campbell, 1681 (Box 145, Folder 2661)
        - Suits for debt, 1681-86 (Box 145, Folder 2662)
        - Disposition by Mungo Campbell to Mungo Campbell, 1704 (Box 145, Folder 2663)
      - Clews joined
        - Tacks, 1735-53 (Box 145, Folder 2664)
        - Sale to Alexander Boswell, 1753-56 (Box 145, Folder 2665-66)
        - Wrappers, n.d. (Box 145, Folder 2667)
    - Craighead
      - Progress of the writs
        - Confirmation to John Rob (Box 146, Folder 2668)
        - Dispositions and receipts, 1662-76 (Box 146, Folder 2669-70)
        - Testament dative of William Morton, 1686 (Box 146, Folder 2671)
        - Suits for debt and assignations, 1687-95 (Box 146, Folder 2672-77)
        - Discharge to John Rob, 1703 (Box 146, Folder 2678)
        - Dispositions and sasine to John Rob, 1704-06 (Box 146, Folder 2679)
        - Assignation of a bond by Rob, 1707 (Box 146, Folder 2680)
        - Suit for debt by Boswell against Rob, 1739 (Box 146, Folder 2681)
        - Agreement by the creditors, 1776 (Box 146, Folder 2681)
        - Marriage contract
    - Dalblair
      - Disposition, 1763 (Box 146, Folder 2682)
    - Overmeiklewood group (Tenshillingside)
      - Inventories of the writs, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 2683-84)
      - Progresses of the writs
        Overmeiklewood 10 shilling land
        Charter to James Mitchell
        - Sasine for James Mitchell, 1556 (Box 146, Folder 2685)
        - Charter to James Mitchell
        - Charter and confirmation to Thomas Mitchell
        - Resignation and sasine for Thomas Mitchell, 1567 (Box 146, Folder 2686)
        - Sasine for Thomas Mitchell, 1587 (Box 146, Folder 2687)
        - Charter and sasine for Janet and John Mitchell, 1591 (Box 146, Folder 2688)
        - Marriage contract of Hugh Mitchell and Janet Morison, 1630 (Box 146, Folder 2689)
        - Disposition by Loudoun to John Mitchell, 1719 (Box 146, Folder 2690)
        - Unsubscribed charter to Hugh Mitchell, n.d. (Box 146, Folder 2691)
      - Overmeiklewood half mark land
        - Charter and sasine for William Richart, 1583 (Box 146, Folder 2692)
        - Charter for William Richart
        - Charter and sasine by Richart to John Murray (Box 146, Folder 2693)
        - Sasine for George Murray, 1594 (Box 146, Folder 2694)
        - Reversion by Robert Mitchell of Logan to Allan Wilson, 1596 (Box 146, Folder 2694)
        - Clare constat for George Murray, 1630 (Box 147, Folder 2695)
        - Sasine for John Murray, 1641 (Box 147, Folder 2696)
        - Disposition, charter, and sasine by John Murray to Hugh Mitchell, 1641 (Box 147, Folder 2697-99)
        - Unsubscribed clare constat to John Mitchell, n.d. (Box 147, Folder 2700)
      - Overmeiklewood five shilling land
        Charter and sasine for Andrew Mitchell
      - Overmeiklewood called Martinshill
        Charter for Robert Fisher
        - Charter for Andrew Fisher, 1574 (Box 147, Folder 2701)
        - Sasine for George Campbell, 1575 (Box 147, Folder 2702)
        - Charter of alienation by Robert Fisher to George Campbell
        - Sasine by Robert Fisher to William Campbell, 1577 (Box 147, Folder 2703)
        - Charter by Robert Fisher to Andrew Mitchell, 1578 (Box 147, Folder 2704)
      - Overmeiklewood general
        - Receipts of feu duty paid by Robert Mitchell, 1684-91 (Box 147, Folder 2705)
        - Disposition by Mitchell to Robert McGavin, 1699 (Box 147, Folder 2706)
        - Disposition by McGavin to Matthew Miller, 1700 (Box 147, Folder 2707)
        - Memorial and declaration, 1700 (Box 147, Folder 2708)
        - Sasine for Matthew Miller, 1701 (Box 147, Folder 2709)
        - Commission of factorie to John Mitchell, 1713 (Box 147, Folder 2710)
        - Charter and sasine by the Earl of Loudoun to John Mitchell, 1719, 1722 (Box 147, Folder 2711-12)
        - Disposition by Mitchell to John Mitchell, 1723 (Box 148, Folder 2713)
        - Discharge by Young to Mitchell, 1731 (Box 148, Folder 2714)
        - Disposition and sasine by Mitchell to Allan Mitchell, 1732 (Box 148, Folder 2715)
        - Bond by Boswell to Mitchell, 1741 (Box 148, Folder 2716)
        - Disposition by Miller to Boswell, 1756 (Box 148, Folder 2717)
      - Receipts, 1641-1777 (Box 148, Folder 2718-21)
      - Wrappers n.d. (Box 148, Folder 2722)
    - Watersyde purchase
      - Inventories of the writs, 1748 (Box 149, Folder 2723)
      - Progresses of the writs
        - Resignation and sasine by Marie Reid to John Cochrane, 1681 (Box 149, Folder 2724-25)
        - Charter for John Cochrane, 1688 (Box 149, Folder 2726)
        - Disposition and sasine by Mitchell to Cochrane, 1706 (Box 149, Folder 2727)
        - Bonds and discharges: John Cochrane, 1717-30 (Box 149, Folder 2728)
        - Excambion with James Boswell, 1736 (Box 149, Folder 2729)
        - Articles of roup, 1738-58, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2730)
        - Resignations to the trustees of John Cochrane of Watersyde, 1739 (Box 149, Folder 2731-32)
        - Sale to Alexander Boswell, 1740-49 (Box 149, Folder 2733-38)
        - Kirkland memorial (Box 149, Folder 2739)
        - Rental accounts, n.d. (Box 149, Folder 2740)
    - Whiteflats purchase
      - Inventories of the writs, 1739, n.d. (Box 150, Folder 2741-42)
      - Progresses of the writs (3 s land)
        "Middlewhiteflats called Netherwhiteflat"
        - Tack for Donald Waddell, 1548 (Box 150, Folder 2743)
        - Charter for Donald Waddell
        - Sasines for Donald Waddell, 1555, 1556 (Box 150, Folder 2744)
        - Confirmation for Donald Waddell
        - Charter for Donald Waddell
        - Sasine for Donald Waddell, 1580 (Box 150, Folder 2745)
        - Charter for Donald Waddell and Janet Sun, 1593 (Box 150, Folder 2746)
        - Charter of the 12 p land by Waddell for John Wilson, 1596 (Box 150, Folder 2747)
        - Sasine by Waddell for Waddell, 1596 (Box 150, Folder 2748)
        - Charter and sasine by Waddell for Wilson and Agnes Waddell, 1609 (Box 150, Folder 2749-50)
        - Charter by Lord Loudoun confirming Wilson's charters, 1618 (Box 150, Folder 2751)
        - Disposition and sasine by John Wilson to William Hunter and Agnes Wilson, 1651 (Box 150, Folder 2752)
        - Sasine of an annual rent for Agnes Wilson, 1655 (Box 150, Folder 2753)
        - Precept, retour, and sasine for William Hunter, 1673 (Box 150, Folder 2754-56)
        - Disposition and sasine by William Hunter to Adam Beg, 1685 (Box 150, Folder 2757-58)
        - Disposition and sasine by Adam Beg to William Anderson, 1689 (Box 150, Folder 2759-60)
        - Disposition and sasine by Anderson to James Wilson, 1699 (Box 151, Folder 2761-62)
        - Retour for Joseph Wilson, 1717 (Box 151, Folder 2763)
        - Tacks, 1737-39 (Box 151, Folder 2764)
        - Nine shilling land of Nether Catrine called Whiteflats (Overwhiteflats)
          - Extract of James Wilson's rental, [1540?] (Box 151, Folder 2765)
          - Charter and sasine for James Wilson
          - Sasine for James Wilson, 1556 (Box 151, Folder 2766)
          - Resignation by John Wilson to James Wilson, 1583 (Box 151, Folder 2767)
          - Clare constat for J. Wilson (Box 151, Folder 2768-69)
          - Charters for James Wilson
          - Charter and sasine by Loudoun for John Wilson, 1622 (Box 151, Folder 2770-71)
          - Sasine for James Wilson, 1645 (Box 151, Folder 2772)
          - Sasine for Agnes Millar, 1655 (Box 151, Folder 2773)
          - Disposition, charter, and sasine by Wilson for John Wilson, 1662 (Box 151, Folder 2774-76)
          - Disposition by John Wilson to John Hervie, 1692, 1696 (Box 151, Folder 2777-78)
        - Nether Catrine called Kensty (Overwhiteflats)
          - Transumpt charter and sasine for George Mitchell, 1555 (Box 151, Folder 2779)
          - Royal charter for George Mitchell
          - Charter by James Mitchell to William Mitchell, 1597 (Box 151, Folder 2780)
          - Charter by John Farquhar for John Wilson, 1623 (Box 151, Folder 2781)
          - Charter by Loudoun for John Wilson
          - Resignation and sasine by Farquhar for Wilson, 1624 (Box 151, Folder 2782-83)
          - Charter by John Wilson for James Wilson, 1645 (Box 152, Folder 2784)
          - Charter by George Mitchell to William Mitchell, 1656 (Box 152, Folder 2785)
        - Crossblair and Catrineholm
          - Sasine for Bernard Mitchell, 1591 (Box 152, Folder 2786)
          - Royal charter for John Smith of Boigend, 1662 (Box 152, Folder 2787)
        - General
          - Disposition and sasine by John Wilson and John Hervie to James Wilson, 1697 (Box 152, Folder 2788-89)
          - Sale to Alexander Boswell, 1739 (Box 152, Folder 2790)
  - LAND RECORDS
    - Barnside, 1765 (Box 152, Folder 2791)
    - Bellowmiln, 1775 (Box 152, Folder 2791)
    - Boighead, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2792)
    - Braehead
      - Accounts, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2793)
      - Bills and receipts, 1731-49, n.d. (Box 152, Folder 2794)
      - Mitchell-Reid debt progress, 1723-50 (Box 152, Folder 2795-2801)
      - Mitchell-Reid debt progress, 1750-56 (Box 153, Folder 2802-04)
      - Wrappers, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 2805)
    - Bridgend, 1757 (Box 153, Folder 2806)
    - Burnside, 1764 (Box 153, Folder 2806)
    - Falls lands, 1764-74 (Box 153, Folder 2807)
    - Glenmuir, 1769 (Box 153, Folder 2808)
    - Glensyde, 1774 (Box 153, Folder 2809)
    - Kingzeancleuch (Willockston), 1760-63 (Box 153, Folder 2810)
    - Nether Tarreoch, 1742 (Box 153, Folder 2811)
    - Parliament clos house, 1761 (Box 153, Folder 2812)
    - Pennyland
      - Disposition to the Earl of Dumfries, 1751 (Box 153, Folder 2813)
  - LEGAL PAPERS
    - James Boswell
      - "Bundle 1: Assignations", 1718-30, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 2814-17)
      - "Bundle 2: Marriage contracts", 1732, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 2818-19)
      - "Bundle 3: Dispositions", 1718-34, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 2820-24)
      - "Bundle 4: Drafts", 1700-28, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 2825-27)
      - "Bundle 5: Life-rents and bonds of provision", 1703-43, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 2828-32)
      - "Bundle 6:", 1697-1730 (Box 154, Folder 2833-35)
      - "Bundle 7: Heritable bonds and minutes of sale", 1725-29, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 2836-39)
      - "Bundle 8:", 1712-37 (Box 155, Folder 2840-41)
      - "Bundle 9:" (Box 155, Folder 2842-51)
      - Inventory of writs, 1742, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2852)
      - Legal manuscript, [1730?] (Box 156, Folder 2853)
      - Style book, [1685?] (Box 156, Folder 2854)
  - PARISH RECORDS
    - Auchinleck parish
      - Financial papers, 1751-58, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2855)
      - Memorials, 1750-80, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2856)
      - Schoolmaster's salary receipts, 1770-79 (Box 156, Folder 2856)
    - Mauchline parish
      - Schoolmaster's salary receipts, 1773-79 (Box 156, Folder 2857)
    - Ochiltree parish
      - Ministerial receipts, 1757-80, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2858)
    - Sorn parish
      - Financial papers, 1759-79 (Box 156, Folder 2859)
    - Sorn and Mauchline parishes
      - Decreets of locality, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 2860)
  - OVERSIZE
    - Memorial on the titles 1774? (Box 157, Folder 2861)
    - Burgess tickets
      - Aberdeen, 1756 (Box 157, Folder 2862)
      - Ayr ticket, 1719 (Box 157, Folder 2863)
      - Banff, 1752 (Box 157, Folder 2864)
      - Brechlin, 1758 (Box 157, Folder 2865)
      - Culross, 1723 (Box 157, Folder 2866)
      - Dumbarton, 1760 (Box 157, Folder 2867)
      - Dumfries, 1756 (Box 157, Folder 2867)
      - Elgin, 1757 (Box 158, Folder 2868)
      - Galloway, 1782 (Box 158, Folder 2869)
      - Glasgow, 1755 (Box 158, Folder 2870)
      - Inverary, 1755 (Box 158, Folder 2871)
      - Inverness, 1756 (Box 158, Folder 2872)
      - Irvine, 1729 (Box 158, Folder 2873)
      - Jedburgh, 1756 (Box 158, Folder 2874)
      - Kilmarnock, 1719 (Box 159, Folder 2875)
      - Kircaldy, 1756 (Box 159, Folder 2876)
      - Lochmaben, 1756 (Box 159, Folder 2877)
      - Montrose, 1757 (Box 159, Folder 2878)
      - Paisley, 1768 (Box 159, Folder 2879)
      - Peebles, 1759 (Box 159, Folder 2880)
      - Perth, 1756 (Box 160, Folder 2881)
      - Sanquhar, 1731 (Box 160, Folder 2882)
      - Selkirk, 1759 (Box 160, Folder 2883)
      - Stirling, 1730, 1755 (Box 160, Folder 2884-85)
      - Whithorn, 1748 (Box 161, Folder 2886)
      - Wigtown, 1748 (Box 161, Folder 2887)
    - Land purchases
      Carbello
      - Charter of Gass by Whitfoord for Campbell, 1630 (Box 161, Folder 2888)
      - Charter and confirmation for John Wallace of Dundonald, 1552-53 (Box 161, Folder 2889)
      - Charter by the minister of Ffailford, 1575 (Box 162, Folder 2890)
      - Charter by the Wallaces, 1587 (Box 162, Folder 2891)
      - Royal charter and sasine for George Reid, 1606 (Box 162, Folder 2892-93)
      - Clews
        - Charter and confirmation for John Campbell, 1555, 1557 (Box 162, Folder 2894-95)
        - Royal charter to David Campbell, 1590 (Box 163, Folder 2896)
        - Charter and confirmation for Robert Fisher, 1555, 1557 (Box 163, Folder 2897-98)
        - Clare constat for Robert Fisher, 1579 (Box 163, Folder 2899)
        - Charter for James McLanochan, 1595 (Box 164, Folder 2900)
        - Charter for George Campbell, 1604 (Box 164, Folder 2901)
        - Craighead, n.d. (Box 164, Folder 2902)
      - Overmeiklewood
        - Charters to James Mitchell, 1555, 1559 (Box 164, Folder 2903-04)
        - Charter to Thomas Mitchell, 1567 (Box 164, Folder 2905)
        - Confirmation to Thomas Mitchell, 1567 (Box 165, Folder 2906)
        - Charter for William Richart, 1584 (Box 165, Folder 2907)
        - Charter for John Murray, 1589 (Box 165, Folder 2908)
        - Charters and sasine for Andrew Mitchell, 1555, 1577 (Box 165, Folder 2909-12)
      - Whiteflats
        - Charter and sasine for Daniel Waddell, 1555 (Box 166, Folder 2913)
        - Confirmation for Donald Waddell, 1557 (Box 166, Folder 2914)
        - Charter for Donald Waddell, 1579 (Box 166, Folder 2915)
        - Charter and sasine for James Wilson, 1555 (Box 166, Folder 2916-17)
        - Charters for James Wilson, 1583 (Box 167, Folder 2918-19)
        - Charter for George Mitchell, 1590 (Box 167, Folder 2920)
        - Charter for John Wilson, 1624 (Box 167, Folder 2921)
- James Boswell (1740-1795), 1733-1795; Series XVII; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Series XVII fills Boxes 168-71 and has been arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - BARONY RECORDS
    - Charters, 1784 (Box 168, Folder 2922-23)
    - Sasines, 1784 (Box 168, Folder 2924-25)
  - ESTATE PAPERS
    - Accounts
      - "Cash", 1791 (Box 168, Folder 2926)
      - Haymaking, 1793 (Box 168, Folder 2927)
      - "Improvements to the Entailed Estate", 1787-95 (Box 168, Folder 2928-30)
      - Servants wages, 1783-95 (Box 168, Folder 2931-32)
      - Summary accounts, 1789 (Box 168, Folder 2933)
    - Bills and receipts
      - Estate work, 1783-95, n.d. (Box 169, Folder 2934)